Guide to the Stanford University Objects Collection SC1048
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Objects
  - Button from 50th reunion of class of 1951, ARCH-AM-2001-31 (Box 1)
  - Button with photo of John B. Ford with words circling it: Brilliant...Wise...Passionate...Rare...Leader...Strategist, ARCH-AM-2008-003 (Box 1)
  - Button, "class of '60, Stanford." white letters on red, 6cm diam., ARCH-AM-1984-37 (Box 1)
  - Button, 25th reunion class of '54, white with red "S", 6cm diam., ARCH-AM-1984-35 (Box 1)
  - Button, 5.8 cm. Red background. Stanford Job Faire, 1979; ARCH-AM-00-199 (Box 1)
  - Button, class of '65, white, red "S" and "'65". 5cm diam., ARCH-AM-1984-36 (Box 1)
  - Button, class of '67, white letters, red bkg "67 the last great class Stanford," 3cm diam., ARCH-AM-1984-38 (Box 1)
  - Button, metal, red bkg. on white letter. Stanford Class of '30- 45th reunion. 10cm. diam. pin on back., ARCH-AM-1980-20 (Box 1)
  - Button: LSJU Portfolio Project, ARCH-AM-1994-09 (Box 1)
  - Button: "Beat Cal 1981, Tresidder Union" red bkg, black letters, 5cm diam., ARCH-AM-1984-47 (Box 1)
  - Button: "celebrate stanford: 1997 celebrate founders day" with photo of the 3 Stanfords, ARCH-AM-1997-004 (Box 1)
  - Button: "Don't waste the power: Vote"; red & white, ARCH-AM-1992-18 (Box 1)
  - Button: "Once an Indian Always an Indian", circa 1949; ARCH-AM-2016-001 (Box 1)
    (3 in. diameter) with Lil Injun face
  - Button: "Reagan Library" with internat'l no symbol [circle with slash], ARCH-AM-1992-19 (Box 1)
  - Button: "SULA volunteer" and drawing of an elephant, ARCH-AM-1999-012 (Box 1)
  - Button: "Thanks! Stanford Employee Recognition Day. Friday, September 25, 1992", ARCH-AM-1992-16 (Box 1)
  - Button: "Welcome! 1999 Orientation" with "S" inside compass-type circle (2), ARCH-AM-1999-024 (Box 1)
  - Button: Beat Cal with image of bear with red diagonal stripe over it [universal "not" symbol], ARCH-AM-2006-018 (Box 1)
  - Button: Big Game, 1978; ARCH-AM-1992-03 (Box 1)
  - Button: Celebrate Stanford Founders' Day April 5, 1998 (2) Includes photo of Leland, Jane, and Leland Jr. in center, ARCH-AM-1998-004 (Box 1)
  - Button: I [heart] FRESHMEN, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-006 (Box 1)
  - Button: New Student Orientation 2003 Welcome (6 buttons), ARCH-AM-2003-022 (Box 1)
  - Button: New Student Orientation 2004 Welcome (4 buttons), ARCH-AM-2007-002 (Box 1)
  - Button: New Student Orientation 2005 Welcome (5 buttons), ARCH-AM-2007-003 (Box 1)
  - Button: Service at Stanford Public Service Reunion 2000, ARCH-AM-2001-01 (Box 1)
  - Button: Stanford '51. White background. Red lettering., ARCH-AM-2017-014 (Box 1)
  - Button: Stanford Half Century Club 1926 1976 * We Made It! *, ARCH-AM-2004-026 (Box 1)
  - Button: Stanford Savoyards - 40 year anniversary, 2013; ARCH-AM-2016-006 (Box 1)
  - Button: STUDY AT TMU open 'round the clock for finals, ARCH-AM-2002-15 (Box 1)
  - Button: Sun Bowl. Stanford Alumni. Orange Sun wearing Nerd Nation Glasses., 2016 Dec 30; ARCH-AM-2017-012 (Box 1)
  - Button: Welcome to Stanford 2002 Orientation, ARCH-AM-2002-28 (Box 1)
    5 buttons, all the same (2002-28.1 - 2002-28.5)
  - Button: Welcome to Stanford! New Student Orientation 2006 (4 items), ARCH-AM-2008-007 (Box 1)
  - Buttons (2) from 1999 Founders Day: "Celebrate Stanford! Founders' Day April 11, 1999" with photo of Leland, Jane, and Leland Jr., ARCH-AM-1999-007 (Box 1)
  - Buttons (2) from 20th anniversery of Tresidder Memorial Union: "TMU was built in 1962, where were you?", ARCH-AM-1991-091 (Box 1)
  - Buttons (2) from Fast for Life, April 30, 1998, during Cesar Chavez Commemmoration Week, ARCH-AM-1999-002 (Box 1)
  - Buttons (4) from Reunion Homecoming Weekend, 2015; ARCH-AM-2016-005; 3 items (Box 1)
    ARCH-AM.2016-005.1 - I met my BEST FRIEND at Stanford ARCH-AM.2016-005.2 - I met my PARTNER at Stanford ARCH-AM.2016-005.3 - I met my HUSBAND at Stanford ARCH-AM.2016-005.4 - I met my WIFE at Stanford
    Stanford Alumni Association
  - Buttons (5): New Student Orientation 2004 Welcome; New Student Orientation 2005 Welcome; New Student Orientation 2006 Welcome; Red and White horizontal stripes with "Stanford" in script; "I [heart] Freshmen & Transfers" with white background. Pin (1): "Stanford Centennial - 100th Class 1990," pinned on paper that says "Stanford 100 Years.", ARCH-AM-2009-034 (Box 1)
    2009-034.1 New Student Orientation 2004 Welcome button 2009-034.2 New Student Orientation 2005 Welcome button 2009-034.3 New Student Orientation 2006 Welcome button 2009-034.4 Red and White horizontal stripes with "Stanford" in script button 2009-034.5 I [heart] Freshmen & Transfers button 2009-034.6 Stanford Centennial 100th Class 1990 pin
  - Buttons (5): Various, ARCH-AM.2014-018; 5 item(s) (Box 1)
    ARCH-AM.2014-018.1 "I [heart] Frosh" ARCH-AM.2014-018.2 "I [heart] Frosh" ARCH-AM.2014-018.3 "Celebrate Stanford! Founders' Day" ARCH-AM.2014-018.4 "I [heart] Freshman" ARCH-AM.2014-018.5 "We're Rose Bowl Bound!!!"
  - Buttons (all different, with cartoons or graphics), ARCH-AM-2008-013 (Box 1)
    013.1 Robotics 013.2 Architecture 013.3 Compilers 013.4 CAD 013.5 Office Systems 013.6 Algorithms 013.7 Human Interfaces 013.8 Numerical Analysis 013.9 Verification 013.10 Human Interfaces 013.11 Networks 013.12 Expert Systems 013.13 Distributed Systems 013.14 Natural Languages 013.15 Programming Environments013.16 Computer Graphics 013.17 Theory 013.18 VLSI 013.19 Programming Languages 013.20 Reliability
  - Buttons and a pin from alumni reunions, ARCH-AM-2001-33 (Box 1)
    33.1 Stanford '41 / '91 Half Century Club 33.2 Stanford Half Century Club 1926 / 1976 33.3 Stanford Half Century Club '43 [1993] 33.4 Stanford Class Reunion 1988 33.5 Stanford 1940-1990 Fiftieth [lapel pin]
  - Buttons and badges (Stanford athletics) mounted in two albums (56 items total), ARCH-AM-1985-07 (Box 1)
  - Buttons from football games, ARCH-AM-2001-34 (Box 1)
    34.1 Big Game Bear Hunt 34.2 Stanford vs. Notre Dame 10/3/92 34.3 Stanford @ Notre Dame October 1, 1988
  - Buttons issued for the 1983 visit of Queen Elizabeth on campus - "Stanford University 1983 Queen Elizabeth" - attached to card from President and Mrs. Donald Kenndy, with message "A memento of the Queen's Visit. Jeanne and Don" (3 copies), ARCH-AM-2008-015 (Box 1)
  - Buttons metal. white bkg with '30 in red letters. 9cm diam. pin on back (two identical buttons), ARCH-AM-1980-18 (Box 1)
  - Buttons, celebrating opening of bookstore expansion, summer 1978 (4); Stanford Christmas faire (2), ARCH-AM-1979-06 (Box 1)
    79-06.1 and .2 I Read Books for the Stanford Bookstore 79-06.3 Welcome to the Stanford Bookstore 79-06.4 Join Our Book Club 25% off bestsellers 79-96.5 and .6 Stanford Christmas Faire
  - Buttons, mostly Indian theme, circa 1950s; ARCH-AM-2003-004 (Box 1)
    004.1 lil injun pointing to himself 004.2 lil injun in football uniform 004.3 indian with axe leaning on Cal bear 004.4 indian with axe sitting on Cal bear 004.5 lil injun head superimposed over "S" 004.6 "Hitch up to the Wiggin Wagon" 004.7 indian head with feather headdress 004.8 "BEAT UCLA" 004.9 "BEAT CAL"
  - Buttons: "Summer Job Fair" (yellow and blue); "Study at TMU" black and yellow. n.d., ARCH-AM-1984-13 (Box 1)
  - Buttons: Beat Cal 1977 and Spring Fling 1979, ARCH-AM-2004-009 (Box 1)
    009.1 BEAT CAL BIG GAME '77; 009.2 Spring Fling '79
  - Buttons: metal, red bkg, white letters, class of '30, 40th reunion, Stanford. (Denny Driggs, 10cm, diam., pin on back). two= identical, ARCH-AM-1980-19 (Box 1)
  - Buttons. Metal pin-on buttons for holidays and other events. 1978, 1982, 1983., ARCH-AM-1984-02 (Box 1)
    1984-02.1 Harvest October 1 1984-02.2 Coffee House 2 years and growing Anniversary '82 1984-02.3 Stanford Christmas Faire Dec. 4-6 [1983?] 1984-02.4 Staff Stanford Christmas Faire [1983?] 1984-02.5 Beat Cal Big Game '78 [image of Gryphon?] 1984-02.6 Beat Cal Big Game '78 [axe head image]
  - Buttons, (6 coat, 8 sleeve) with Stanford seal, gold, white, and red; belonged to Deal "Bud" Christensen, Jr., Class of 1951., Accession ARCH-AM-2017-006 (Box 1)
  - C.P. Jupiter / U.P. 119 Centennial Locomotive Set / The Golden Spike - 0 scale models of 2 locomotives that met at Promontory, Utah; in own large wooden box.[Originally given to Cantor Center on Sept. 4, 2001, which sent it to the Archives.], ARCH-AM-2001-30 (Box 1)
  - Calendar for 1883 "With Best Wishes for Many Happy Returns of the Day" - pasted on board with fringe and pink braid trim, ARCH-AM-2004-024 (Box 1)
  - Calligraphy, about University Archives. frame 58-45cm, image 51x33cm., ARCH-AM-00-329 (Box 1)
  - Calligraphy, re Bender Room. 51 x 32 cm.REMOVED AND CLASSED AS PRINT 306, ARCH-AM-00-324 (Box 1)
  - Candle Stick & label: 5.5 diam. x 3 cm hi. Belonged to President Madison, for melting sealing wax., ARCH-AM-00-251 (Box 1)
  - cane with metal cap: "Stanford '95", ARCH-AM-1995-23 (Box 1)
  - Cane, with silver plates engraved with yearly editorial staff of the Chapparal (1920-1925), ARCH-AM-00-007 (Box 1)
  - Canvas bag. Front: STANFORD UNIVERSITY with square containing "S", the Tree, the seal, and "U". Back: Compliments of Stanford Bookstore. Red ink on natural canvas, ARCH-AM-2002-37 (Box 1)
  - Cap and Gown pins (3 of same design but from different times) - gold with black enamel in shape of mortar board cap, ARCH-AM-2008-020 (Box 1)
    2008-020.1 "Hazel Levery '07" on back 2008-020.2 blank on reverse 2008-020.3 initials E. J. on back
  - Cap, beanie, red., ARCH-AM-00-171 (Box 1)
  - Cap: Stanford Class of '80 Five Year Reunion, ARCH-AM-2006-020 (Box 1)
  - Card file (3x5) used by Elliott for notes on Stanford History, ARCH-AM-1995-18 (Box 1)
  - Card. 9x5 cm. "I have worked on class of 1918 Bonfire.", ARCH-AM-00-195 (Box 1)
  - Cardboard accompanying the above drawings. "Zoology Dept. Painted cloth materials.", ARCH-AM-00-130.27 (Box 1)
  - Carpet Board: Lil Injun figures, with Stanford spelled out on their backs, ARCH-AM-1994-11 (Box 1)
  - Case for razors., ARCH-AM-00-151.3 (Box 1)
  - Catalog. "Psychological and Physiological Apparatus and Supplies." 1930, ARCH-AM-00-107.1 (Box 1)
  - Cement block memorial plaque: "In Memory of Alan Brown 1956-1979". Removed due to landscape construction [location not specified]., ARCH-AM-2005-014 (Box 1)
  - Cement tiles from Hanna House, ARCH-AM-2005-026 (Box 1)
  - Cent. Award presented to Dept. of Special Collections: sandstone rocks and replica of trowel, ARCH-AM-1991-097 (Box 1)
  - Centennial Banner flown on space shuttle Columbia, 1990; ARCH-AM-1994-02 (Box 1)
  - Centennial Banners (large)., ARCH-AM-1991-099 (Box 1)
    1991-099.1 Red & white nylon "Stanford 100 Years" with stylized tree1991-099.2 Red nylon with unrecognized design element 1991-099.3 Red & white nylon with stylized design of Quad column head 1991-099.4 Red & white nylon with stylized palm trees 1991-099.5-7 White & beige with red Centennial logo [.6 and .7 still in unopened plastic bags] 1991-099.8-9 Turquoise nylon with stylized palm trees 1991-099.10 Turquoise nylon with stylized design of Quad column head 1991-099.11 Red nylon with stylized design of Quad column head 1991-099.12 Red nylon with abstract figures 1991-099.13 White & beige possibly with Stanford 100 [too large] 1991-099.14 White & beige possibly with Stanford 100 [too large] 1991-099.15 White & beige possibly with Stanford 100 [too large] 1991-099.16 White & beige possibly with Stanford 100 [too large] 1991-099.17 Red nylon with stylized design of Quad column head 1991-099.18 Beige with Centennial logo 1991-099.19 Red with abstract figures ? 1991-099.20 [Beige, still in plastic bag] 1991-099.21 [Beige, still in plastic bag] 1991-099.22 [overlarge red nylon - more than one, but too large to unfold]
  - Centennial Medallions (silver and bronze), ARCH-AM-1994-06 (Box 1)
  - Centennial memorabilia, ARCH-AM-1995-05 (Box 1)
    1. Cent. commencement pin, 1991 2. Cent. 100th class pin, 1991 3. Centennial pin 4. T-shirt: Centennial Finale Weekend, 1991
  - Centennial memorabilia - cup and pin, ARCH-AM-1992-12 (Box 1)
    Plastic cup - Parents' Weekend and Founders Day 1991 (2) Pin - "Preparing for the Next 100 Years"
  - Ceramic box in the shape of the Stanford house in Sacramento, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-029 (Box 1)
  - Ceramic Tile with tinted picture of Leland Jr. 24x16x.5 cm, tinted photo, head and shoulders., ARCH-AM-00-248 (Box 1)
  - Ceramic ware, Stanford dinnerware., ARCH-AM.2014-015 (Box 1)
    4 piece dinnerware set with gold rim. Plates and bowl have "Stanford University" at top in gold and white letters and Stanford seal on left, right, and bottom of each piece. Cup has Stanford seal on it.
  - Ceremonial sword of T. Hopkins, with scabard., ARCH-AM-2001-018 (Box 1)
  - Certificate for Japanese Student Assoc.1914, 51x53 cm. black frame with glass. From State of California., ARCH-AM-00-113 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, Framed in glass. 29X41 cm. Wm H. Bonsall, Admission to California State Bar, 1938, ARCH-AM-00-183 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, framed with glass. 25X31 cm. W.H.Bonsall, US District Court, qualifies as attorney., ARCH-AM-00-182 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, framed; gives Timothy Hopkins life privileges to Levi Cooper Lane. Library of Med. & Surgery; frame 41x49, image 35x42 cm., ARCH-AM-00-279 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, Framed. 40X29 cm. Inscribes Leland Stanford's name on immortals of florence nightingale Inst., ARCH-AM-00-180 (Box 1)
  - Champagne bottle: Stanford / Governor's Cuvee / Champagne of California (Weibel Vineyards), ARCH-AM-00-005 (Box 1)
  - Champagne bottle: Stanford Governors Cuvee by Leland Stanford Winery Mission San Jose, Calif., ARCH-AM-1984-51 (Box 1)
  - Champagne flutes from Viennese Ball 2000 and 2001, ARCH-AM-2007-018 (Box 1)
    2007-018.1 2000 Ball; 2007-018.2 2001 Ball
  - Champagne glass, "Stanford Class of 1918 Golden Anniversary", 1968; ARCH-AM-1978-08 (Box 1)
  - Charter of Society of Sigma Xi, LSJU chapter, 1901, ARCH-AM-1979-01 (Box 1)
  - Cigar box "La Flor Stanford" with illustrations on inside lid of Leland Stanford, state capital, and stock farm, ARCH-AM-1992-09 (Box 1)
  - Cigar box, "Leland Stanford", 1898; ARCH-AM-2018-002 (Box 1)
  - Circle of Friends award to Stanford University from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People 2003. Lucite shape with etched letters. 9 in. high, 3.5 in. wide., ARCH-AM-2006-029 (Box 1)
  - Class hat; red beanie (sophomore ?), 1906; ARCH-AM-00-048 (Box 1)
  - Class hat; pith helmet, 1913; ARCH-AM-00-049 (Box 1)
  - Class Ring, 1962, ARCH-AM-2016-004 (Box 1)
    Class ring, belonged to Charles Slaughter, class of 1962.
    Slaughter, Charles H.
  - Cloth diagrams of flowers; used for botany class instruction. 25 pieces, ARCH-AM-00-032 (Box 1)
  - T-shirt-- white cotton (anvil brand) with Leland Jr. portrait on front; L. Jr. "letter" and signature on back., 1981; ARCH-AM-1982-01 (Box 1)
  - Coaster with image of Memorial Church, Memorial Arch, and hills in background., ARCH-AM-00-025 (Box 1)
  - Collage of photographs, university seal, and American flag that were flown aboard the Space Shuttle Atlantis, January 1997; signed by Jeff Wisoff, U. S. Astronaut. Originally given to Bill Stone, president of SAA, ARCH-AM-2001-10 (Box 1)
  - Collection of political pins and buttons of Miss Elizabeth Nash. In square box., ARCH-AM-00-215 (Box 1)
    00-215.1 American flag pin, 1.3x1cm 00-215.2 Medal, 3.5cm diam. Richelieu etc. 00-215.3 Medal, 2cm diam. from S.S. Beaver 00-215.4 Medal, 5cm diam. "Divisao de Geologia." 00-215.5 Button-pin, 2cm "Votes for Women." 00-215.6 Button-pin, 2cm Grant Photo 00-215.7 Button-pin, 6cm "Barclay President" 00-215.8 Button-pin, 6cm Humanity Legion aid to China 00-215.9 Button-pin, 2cm. Liberty, Equality, etc. 00-215.10 Button-pin, 2.5cm "Wilkie for President" 00-215.11 Button-pin, 5.5cm leather - McGovern 00-215.12 Button-pin, 3cm, McGovern-Shriver 00-215.13 Button-pin, 3cm "McGovern" 00-215.14 Button-pin, 3cm, Nixon now more then, etc. 00-215.15 Button-pin, 3cm diam., "Nixon Now" 00-215.16 Button-pin, 5cm, ""Pres. Nixon no more... etc. 00-215.17 Button-pin, 2.5cm, Nixon, gold on black 00-215.18 Button-pin, 2.5cm, "I like Ike" 00-215.19 Button with ribbons - frosty sons of thunder, Somerset County Pa.
  - Commemmorative dinner plate with images of Hoover Tower, inner quad, east gateway, Memorial Church, outer quad, and stadium, ARCH-AM-00-004 (Box 1)
  - Commemorative souvenirs collected by the Centennial office from other institutions' anniversary events, ARCH-AM-1991-101 (Box 1)
    1991-101.1 Pennant from US Olympic Festival '90 1991-101.2 Pennant from US Olympic Festival '90 1991-101.3 Battery operated sparkler from US Olympic Festival '90 1991-101.4 Label pin US Olympic Festival '90 [flag shape] 1991-101.5 Label pin US Olympic Festival '90 [oval] 1991-101.6 Button from 350th Harvard anniversary
  - Community Day Stanford Ultimate Frisbee Team - frisbee [no date on it], ARCH-AM-2006-019 (Box 1)
  - Community Day Stanford Ultimate Frisbee Team - frisbee, ca. 2003, ARCH-AM-2004-030 (Box 1)
  - computer mousepads from SunNet given out at conference. (earth and spacestation Mir on black background) - 6 items, ARCH-AM-1999-005 (Box 1)
  - Concrete sample "Quad Column Approved Sample 10-00-3". Curved piece showing outside ridges. ca. 2000, ARCH-AM-2006-036 (Box 1)
  - Construction materials, circa 2001; ARCH-AM-2002-05 (Box 1)
    2002-05.1 replacement material for ceiling 2002-05.2 frame (possibly original) for soffitt light fixtures in Hobby House [boxed with AM 2002-03] 2002-05.3 sample of original concrete floor 2002-05.4 core sample from terrace
  - Copper plated printing block of image of earthquake-damaged 1900 library; framed, ARCH-AM-2002-12 (Box 1)
  - Corn-cob pipe used in Encina smokers, ARCH-AM-2004-015 (Box 1)
  - Costumes (vests and blouses - 6 items), ARCH-AM-2008-017 (Box 1)
  - Cup, metal. 9cm high. Souvenier of Stanford University, Palo Alto tree, Mem. Arch, Quad, and Chapel entrance., ARCH-AM-00-192 (Box 1)
  - Death Mask: Jordan, David Starr, ARCH-AM-00-067 (Box 1)
  - Death Mask: Stanford, Jane Lathrop, ARCH-AM-00-068 (Box 1)
  - Death Mask: Stanford, Leland Jr., ARCH-AM-00-070 (Box 1)
  - Death Mask: Stanford, Leland, ARCH-AM-00-069 (Box 1)
  - Decal of L'il Injun face, circa 1965; ARCH-AM-2006-005 (Box 1)
  - Decal: Stanford University with "S" and tree placed between, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-017 (Box 1)
  - Delta Tau Delta paddleboard and letter from Fred Glover, names of Delt initiates carved on it., ARCH-AM-1984-56 (Box 1)
  - demi-tasse cup and saucer, painted scene "North Arcade, St. Unive., Ca.", circa 1895; ARCH-AM-1980-25 (Box 1)
  - Demitasse cup belonging to Jessie K. Jordan, ARCH-AM-1979-07 (Box 1)
  - Denim work shirt with SULAIR HighWire Press Stanford University Press embroidered on left front, along with symbol for each., ARCH-AM-2007-012 (Box 1)
  - Die, used for Tree Stamp for Libraries., 1969; ARCH-AM-00-218 (Box 1)
  - Die; 12x3x1 cm. Made by Mesabi Iron Co. S.F., ARCH-AM-00-237 (Box 1)
  - Die; Bookplate, 7x5x2, The Barbara Jordon Library of Birds., ARCH-AM-00-236 (Box 1)
  - Die; Bookplate, ExLibris, Kate Felton Elkins with scenic picture., ARCH-AM-00-234 (Box 1)
  - Die; Bookplate, Leland Stanford University Library, presented by Timothy Welton Stanford. 4x6x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-235 (Box 1)
  - Die; Bookplate, Stanford Univ. Library. 8x5x2 cm. Journalism Library., ARCH-AM-00-232 (Box 1)
  - Die; David Starr Jordan's Book Plate., ARCH-AM-00-252 (Box 1)
  - Die; Group of men under Quad Arch. 15x11x2 cm. (Geology), ARCH-AM-00-224 (Box 1)
  - Die; Insurance Policy from Pacific Mutual on Life of Leland Stanford. 15x10x2., ARCH-AM-00-247 (Box 1)
  - Die; John Almack Memorial Collection. 11x8 cm., ARCH-AM-00-230 (Box 1)
  - Die; Labelled Charles Stanford. 13x10x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-226 (Box 1)
  - Die; Picture of man. 6x9x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-220 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait & Signature of J.C. Branner., ARCH-AM-00-246 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of a man. 8x6x2., ARCH-AM-00-229 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of man, 9x15x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-222 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of Man; 13x10x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-227 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of Man; 16x11cm., ARCH-AM-00-225 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of man. 6x9x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-221 (Box 1)
  - Die; Stanford Church. 11x16x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-223 (Box 1)
  - Die; Stanford University Library bookplate; 9x6x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-231 (Box 1)
  - Die: Stanford Path at Lagunita. 9x12x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-228 (Box 1)
  - Diploma, black frame with glass; 84x108 cm., awarded to David Starr Jordan by Internat. Fisheries Exhibition., ARCH-AM-00-089 (Box 1)
  - Diploma, Harvard University. For Wm Bonsall. 35X39 cm., ARCH-AM-00-184 (Box 1)
  - Doll, Stanford Football Player. 14cm high, in red sweater with block "S". [sticker on bottom - "Varsity Vic"; copyright Bud Pione carved on back of figure], ARCH-AM-00-194 (Box 1)
  - Donald Tresidder memorabilia, ARCH-AM-1984-58 (Box 1)
    1. academic hood belonging to Pres. Donald Tresidder, purple and blue velvet 2. academic hood belonging to Pres. Donald Tresidder, green and red velvet 3. Pennant ""Stanford"" maroon
  - Double sleigh bed previously owned by Stanford President Ray Lyman Wilbur (from the Dunn-Bacon house), ARCH-AM-1998-020 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin, 61X89 cm. Shasta daisy in color on muslin., circa 1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.04 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. 109X89 Green Crayon drawing. Hyrid poppy leaves, Burbank., ARCH-AM-00-130.02 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X91 cm. Ink drawing. Tall man and short man standing by yardstick. From J.of Heredity vol 5. no.11, Nov.1914., 1914-11; ARCH-AM-00-130.23 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 64X107 cm. Diagrams of Okimonas Termo, Euglena Viridis, Haematococcus & Pandorina., ARCH-AM-00-130.25 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. 66X94 cm. Used for class instruction; Physiological Morphology, 1898. Black Ink. Sea Urchin, extra ovates., ARCH-AM-00-130.01 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 86X61 cm. Subject; artificial selection. Hybrid walnut; cross between Japanese & English walnut., ARCH-AM-00-130.24 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 86X91 cm. Brown crayon on white. Diagram of flower showing pollination (To illustrate method of cross pollination.), ARCH-AM-00-130.11 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 89X107 cm. Leaves from second generation seedlings of walnut., ARCH-AM-00-130.13 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X104 cm. Burbank scarlet poppy hybrid. Colored Crayon., ARCH-AM-00-130.14 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X107 cm. c.1898. Hybridology. Wild stoneless plum and french prune., ARCH-AM-00-130.15 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X114 cm. Artificial selection: Variation in poppy capsules., ARCH-AM-00-130.21 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X114cm. Two pedelled hybrid seedling lily. Color-artificial selection., ARCH-AM-00-130.07 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X130 cm. c.1898. Lecture; Wheat Breeding. Artificial selection., ARCH-AM-00-130.12 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X86 cm. First fixed primus blackberry artifically produced., ARCH-AM-00-130.22 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 97X91 cm. Variation on Hybridization. Half Sour-half sweet apple and half green yellow- half red. "A most remarkable result.", ARCH-AM-00-130.26 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 63X104 cm. Drawings of Amoeba, Chondriodema difforme Dipflugia., circa 1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.16 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 89X61 cm. Artificial selection- original and improved beach plum., circa1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.03 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 104X91 cm. The first double shasta daisy. Curious forms among asta daisey seedlings., circa1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.05 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 48X91 cm. Thallus and fruit of spineless cactus., circa 1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.17 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X117 cm. Seven types of Canaries. Drawn from Romanes. Darwin after Darwin., circa 1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.08 (Box 1)